JARED ACKLEY

Leander, TX 78641

Phone: (419)584-6006 | Email: jrod3323@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jared-ackley-438364124/
GitHub: https://github.com/jrod3323 | Portfolio: https://jrod3323.github.io/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with the goal of propelling companies further and driving organizational growth through the incorporation of technology. 10 years experience developing and streamlining processes in the high stress and demanding field of organ transplant and donation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, Handlebars, React, SASS, JQuery **Back End Skills**: Node.JS, SQL, PHP, JSON, AJAX, API development, MongoDB, MySQLWorkbench, NoSQL **Management Skills**: IT Project Management, Process Development and Streamlining, Git Repo Management

PROJECTS

Covid Travel Planner

https://github.com/jrod3323/Covid_Travel_Planner | https://jrod3323.github.io/Covid_Travel_Planner

- An application to help a User plan trips to social distanced national parks during Covid. The application also supplies the user with the most recent Covid statistics to a selected state.
- Managed the GitHub repo for the team, Developed back-end API routes, Developed front end JS
- JavaScript, JQuery, Materialize CSS framework, Ajax, HTML, CSS

Follow My Fitness

https://github.com/jrod3323/Follow-My-Fitness | https://follow-my-fitness.herokuapp.com/

- A workout application that allows User to store and reference their workouts.
- Front end and Back end JS; Aided front end with Materialize CSS; Crafted API routes; managed file structure
- JavaScript, JQuery, Materialize CSS framework, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Sequelize, MySQL, Express.JS, Node.JS, Handlebars, Passport.JS, Compression, DotENV

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

IT Project Manager Buckeye Transplant Services

2018 - Present Glandorf,OH

Develops IT tools to aid all departments with process standardization and automation. Review processes from all divisions of the company and create tools and programs to automate and streamline processes to improve overall work-flow. Develop and maintain company wide IT policies. Collaborate with outside development teams to improve current Buckeye EMR Charting System.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed auditing tool using GoogleScript and Javascript to streamline quality department auditing process
- Developed Daily Roster for quick guide to daily coordinator on call list using GoogleScript and Javascript
- Streamlined Transplant Center Email communication by building an application using JavaScript to standardize user data input

Additional Experience

Buckeye Transplant Services, Glandorf, OH Clinical Support Manager

2013 - Present 2016-2018

Work to maintain current Buckeye Workflow Processes across all contracted Transplant Centers. Provide support and guidance to all Clinical Coordinators in the company.

Key Accomplishments:

- Develop training modules for all on-coming and current clinical coordinators
- Developed clinical "Workspace" to streamline process and communication between coordinators and transplant centers

Import Transplant Coordinator

2013-2016

Contract Lead that trained new coordinators to covered contracts while maintaining a high level of service to Transplant Center partners

Key Accomplishments:

Spearheaded Buckeye Transplant to aid transplant center to record number of transplants in 2015 Onboarded new transplant center services in 2014

Indiana Organ Procurement Organization, Indianapolis, IN Procurement Transplant Coordinator

2011-2013

Worked with local hospital partners and transplant centers to maximize the gift of organ donation in the state of Indiana.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed Ventilator Management Protocol to maximize lung donation for the state
- Developed Antibiotic therapy protocol to broadly cover donor patients to maximize safety of donated organs for organ recipients

EDUCATION

POST GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

University of Texas at Austin - Austin, TX October 2020 to Present

MASTER'S IN BIOMEDICAL SCIENCES - HUMAN ORGAN DONATION

UNIVERSITY OF TOLEDO - TOLEDO, OH JULY 2010 TO JULY 2011

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN PHARMACEUTICAL IN SCIENCES

UNIVERSITY OF TOLEDO - TOLEDO, OH 2005 TO 2011